Guide to the Homer Folks Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Homer Folks Papers
1890-1963.
Folks, Homer, 1867-1963.
circa 6,000 items (32 boxes, 1 oversized portfolio)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078770
This collection consists of papers and correspondence of Homer Folks, (1897-1963), social worker.
Biographical Note
Social worker.
Scope and Content
Papers and correspondence relating to Folk's activities with the Red Cross after World War I, as a special agent to the military governor of Cuba in 1900, and as president of the New York State Probation Commission, 1907-1917. The collection also reflects his interest in mental hygiene, the care of neglected and delinquent children, tuberculosis, and public health and welfare.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one series:
Series I: Papers
Subjects
American Red Cross.; New York (State).--State Probation Commission.; Cuba--History--1899-1906.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; Social problems.; Mental health.; Children--Institutional care.; Juvenile delinquents.; Tuberculosis.; Public health.; Public welfare.; Social work with children.; Social workers.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: Boxes 2-32. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1970 M-70 New York School of Social Work Transfer
- Series I: Papers
  - Cataloged correspondence (Box 1)
    - Harding, Warren Gamaliel (Box 1)
    - Harriman, W. Averell (Box 1)
    - Hilles, Charles D. (Box 1)
    - Hughes, Charles Evans (Box 1)
    - Lehman, Herbert H. (Box 1)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (Box 1)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 1)
    - Taft, William Howard (Box 1)
  - Cataloged photographs
    - Hine, Lewis W. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - 1890-1898 S (Box 2)
    - 1898 T-1901 (Box 3)
    - 1902-1926 (Box 4)
    - 1927-1942; Louisa Lee Schuyler; Mrs. William Rice (Box 5)
  - Addresses
    - 1891-1912 (Box 6)
    - 1913-1924 (Box 7)
    - 1925-1930 (Box 8)
    - 1931-1935 (Box 9)
    - 1936-1940 (Box 10)
    - 1941-1946 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous writings and addresses (Box 12)
  - Journals
    - 1904-1925 (Box 13)
    - 1926-1942 (Box 14)
  - Appointment books; miscellaneous correspondence (Box 15)
  - College papers (Box 16)
  - New York State Probation Commission Hearings (Box 17)
  - New York State Probation Commission Hearings; State care of children (Box 18)
  - Red Cross; Cuba (Box 19)
  - Personal and biographical material; clippings (Box 20)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 21)
  - Memorabilia and photographs (Box 22-23)
  - Printed (Box 24-26)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 27)
  - Scrapbooks (one per Box) (Box 28-32)
  - Photos, citations, awards, etc. (Box Oversized Portfolio)